Guide to the Xavier University Commencement Programs and Other Material Collection
Xavier University Archives and Special Collections
Xavier University Commencement Programs and Other Material Collection
1920-2012
Xavier University Archives and Special Collections Phone: 513-745-4821 http://www.xavier.edu/cm/archives
Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio). Office of the Registrar
4.5 linear feet ((10 boxes))
A collection of Xavier commencement programs dating from 1920 to the present. The collection may include for a given year other materials associated with the graduation ceremony (e.g. Baccalaureate Mass programs, stage party directions, newspaper clippings, invitations and other materials).
XUA-3
History of Xavier University Commencement Programs
Xavier University commencement programs have been published since 1842. Older programs (1842 to around the early 20th Century) can be found included in the course catalog collection published for each academic year for St. Xavier College (later renamed Xavier University). The present collection is composed of those commencement programs found within the Xavier University Archives that are found separately published for the years 1920 and onwards.
Commencement programs cannot be considered proof of graduation. The names and honors of graduates listed are for purposes of the commencement program and do not represent a final certification of graduation. Contact the Xavier University Registrar's Office for definitive information on graduation status.
Scope and Content
A collection of commencement programs, 1920 - 2012.
Statement of Arrangement
Generally, the collection is arranged chronologically within each box.
Separated Material
Older St. Xavier College commencement programs can be found published within the course catalogs for each academic year. These course catalogs are separately housed within the Xavier University Archives.
Restrictions on Access
This collection is open for research.
Accruals
Future accessions are anticipated.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Subjects:
Commencement Ceremonies; Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio)--Students--Periodicals
Organizations/Corporations:
Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio)
Detailed Description of The Collection
- Box, 1, 1920-1966
  - Collection Information, 1920-1966 (Folder 1)
  - Bound Volume of Commencement Programs, 1932-1966 (Folder 2)
  - Xavier Commencements, 1920-1924 (Folder 3)
  - Xavier Commencements, 1925-1928 (Folder 4)
  - Xavier Commencements, 1929-1932 (Folder 5)
  - Xavier Commencements, 1933-1936 (Folder 6)
  - Xavier Commencements, 1937-1940 (Folder 7)
  - Xavier Commencements, 1941-1943 (Folder 8)
  - Xavier Commencements, 1944-1945 (Folder 9)
- Box 2, 1946-1963
  - Xavier Commencements, 1946-1948 (Folder 1)
  - Xavier Commencements, 1949-1951 (Folder 2)
  - Xavier Commencements, 1952-1954 (Folder 3)
  - Xavier Commencements, 1955-1957 (Folder 4)
  - Xavier Commencements, 1958-1960 (Folder 5)
  - Xavier Commencements, 1961-1963 (Folder 6)
- Box 3, 1964-1975
  - Xavier Commencements, 1964-1966 (Folder 1)
  - Xavier Commencements, 1967-1969 (Folder 2)
  - Xavier Commencements, 1970 (Folder 3)
  - Xavier Commencements, 1971 (Folder 4)
  - Xavier Commencements, 1972 (Folder 5)
  - Xavier Commencements, 1973 (Folder 6)
  - Xavier Commencements, 1974 (Folder 7)
  - Xavier Commencements, 1975 (Folder 8)
- Box 4, 1976-1984
  - Xavier Commencements, 1976 (Folder 1)
  - Xavier Commencements, 1977 (Folder 2)
  - Xavier Commencements, 1978 (Folder 3)
  - Xavier Commencements, 1979 (Folder 4)
  - Xavier Commencements, 1980 (Folder 5)
  - Xavier Commencements, 1981 (Folder 6)
  - Xavier Commencements, 1982 (Folder 7)
  - Xavier Commencements, 1983 (Folder 8)
  - Xavier Commencements, 1984 (Folder 9)
- Box 5, 1985-1990
  - Xavier Commencements, 1985 (Folder 1)
  - Xavier Commencements, 1986 (Folder 2)
  - Xavier Commencements, 1987 (Folder 3)
  - Xavier Commencements, 1988 (Folder 4)
  - Xavier Commencements, 1989 (Folder 5)
  - Xavier Commencements, 1990 (Folder 6)
- Box 6, 1991-1996
  - Xavier Commencements, 1991 (Folder 1)
  - Xavier Commencements, 1992 (Folder 2)
  - Xavier Commencements, 1993 (Folder 3)
  - Xavier Commencements, 1994 (Folder 4)
  - Xavier Commencements, 1995 (Folder 5)
  - Xavier Commencements, 1996 (Folder 6)
- Box 7, 1997-2000
  - Xavier Commencements, 1997 (Folder 1)
  - Xavier Commencements, 1998 (Folder 2)
  - Xavier Commencements, 1999 (Folder 3)
  - Xavier Commencements, 2000 May 13 (Folder 4)
  - Xavier Commencements, 2000 December 17 (Folder 5)
- Box 8, 2001-2005
  - Xavier Commencements, 2001 (Folder 1)
  - Xavier Commencements, 2002 (Folder 2)
  - Xavier Commencements, 2003 (Folder 3)
  - Xavier Commencements, 2004 (Folder 4)
  - Xavier Commencements, 2005 (Folder 5)
- Box 9, 2006-2010
  - Xavier Commencements, 2006 (Folder 1)
  - Xavier Commencements, 2007 (Folder 2)
  - Xavier Commencements, 2008 (Folder 3)
  - Xavier Commencements, 2009 (Folder 4)
  - Xavier Commencements, 2010 (Folder 5)
- Box 10, 2011-
  - Xavier Commencements, 2011 (Folder 1)
  - Xavier Commencements, 2012 (Folder 2)